I think I can definitely be very
productive in the past game still. I
think just cuz you know, one situation
didn't quite work out the way anybody
wanted it doesn't mean you just like
can't do it anymore. But at the end of
the day, I'm just here to
you know, compete to the best of my
ability and you know, help this team in
whatever way I can help this team.
Dustin.
Hey Tyler, what what were your
perceptions of maybe why it didn't go
the way you wanted it to last year and
and how much maybe does that
fuel you to you know, I guess prove
yourself again in this league?
Yeah, I mean I definitely motivation at
all-time high.
Uh
You know, I
There's a there's a lot of different
things that go into it, right? I'm not
going to sit here and talk about it,
right? Sure, it's you know, there's a
lot of pieces to that puzzle. Uh I think
one thing just in you know, LA there was
a very uh
They did they had like personnel-wise
they did stuff very specifically, right?
We had a
you know, very like Ravens like right at
310-lb fullback that did fullback stuff.
We had a big blocker and we had a a guy
that did all the receiving stuff. So
that in my opinion I've always prided
myself on trying to be able to play in
every you know, be able every down tight
end whether it's pass game, run game, uh
pass protection. Uh
And I think there they just they
specialized and kind of had guys that
did like really excelled in one area.
And um so I think just like that in in
general [clears throat] kind of just
maybe hurt my play style, right? Like
I'm not a 280-lb mauler, but I can get
the job done in the run game and I'm not
like the super flashy pass catch pass
catcher, but I can be very productive in
the pass game.
Um and they just kind of had guys that
specialized in it.
Uh so I think that was a big part of it
and then
uh
Yeah, when it comes to just like the
motivation of like how that played out
and being a walk-on in college just kind
of the trajectory of my whole career.
Like I'm very motivated and on top of it
it makes it um
you know, that even got like even more
of a thing just coming here, right? Like
being at home, wanting to be a part of
this. Uh you know, that that even adds
on to it. So um yeah, all those things.
You just mentioned it really quickly
there. Um we've seen this regime bring
in several hometown guys. There's you
know, several Michigan guys that have
been on the roster here.
Um you know, what is the impact of of
playing for the hometown team? I imagine
at some level you grew up a Lions fan.
Yeah, I wish I could say that. I can't
say I was a Lions fan sadly. I don't
want to lie. I think in the past I've
I've said I don't things I wasn't. I
actually my parent my dad grew up a
Bears fan where he's from in Southwest
Detroit uh Southwest uh
Michigan and then at that time me and my
cousin were Packers fans sadly. I think
just to make him mad, our uncles and and
family mad. Uh I think the really neat
thing about just like growing up and
um
You know, I love Michigan. Like I'll
never leave Michigan.
Uh my wife would probably go somewhere
warm if I if I was like, "Hey, let's go
somewhere warm." But I'm just you know,
it's it's you know, my favorite place in
the world. Uh I look for I come back
here every off-season since being in the
NFL. Like I this is my always been our
home base. We live in Michigan. You
know, as soon as the season ends
wherever we've been we've come back to
Michigan.
Uh and just like through that time and
watching like the the city of Detroit
just get better and better year by year.
Watching the fan base just get behind um
you know, the Lions and
uh you know, like there was that you
know, whatever 3 years ago when NFC
Championship or 2 years ago whatever it
was and Michigan wins a national
championship and just watching the state
of Michigan just um you know, rally
behind the football programs here. Uh
and like seeing what it does for a
community and whatnot. You know, I was
always kind of like as I got older and
realized what it did for a city and for
the state of Michigan like I kind of
help but just want them you know, every
Detroit sports team to do good um
especially the Lions. So to come back
here and have the opportunity to be a
part of it and be a part of something
special is uh I didn't realize how
special I would feel about like how
um special it would feel. So definitely
a great opportunity. Thanks. Welcome
home. Appreciate it.
Nolan.
Hey Tyler, how are you doing? Thanks for
joining us today. I I read in a couple
different places, so I hope this is
correct. You uh left Northwood to pursue
a career as a walk-on at Central
Michigan. Um
When when you make a a big gamble and
decision in your life at such a young
age and it pays off in the way it did,
like how does that change the way you
think about the world and what you're
capable of?
Yeah, I mean that's interesting. I like
the way you put it.
Um yeah, so I guess I I played
basketball. I went to Lansing Catholic
High School and always played
basketball. We really bad at football.
I'll try to say it quick. So I go and I
play college basketball. I just feel
like I kind of under like undersold
myself. I should have like I feel like I
should have been playing at a higher
level. I always kind of told my my
parents like I was going to be the first
D1 athlete in the family and then
obviously Northwood is Division II, so I
wasn't. And um
You know, I think like we talk about it
in business, like everybody in their
career no matter what the career is like
there's probably a point in your career
where you have to pivot or in your life
where you have to make a pivot.
Um whether it's
you know, changing completely what you
do or just like tweaking what you're
doing or like at some point you have a
pivot moment that you know, could
possibly make or break the trajectory of
where you're going. Uh
At that time did I know it was like that
big of a a decision and a pivot? Like I
know I was leaving free college to walk
on. But uh
you know, it's kind of just like that
blind faith that you know, I just always
thought I was going to be a professional
athlete. At one point I thought I was
going to be basketball. That pivot was
okay, maybe it's it's it's not going to
be basketball. It's it's got to be
football. And um
Yeah, I mean I just I think part of it
is just like that delusional faith that
like you can do whatever you put your
mind to and you know, if you're willing
to work hard enough at it that you know,
it's possible.
Um and that's kind of where I get when I
look back at it is like you know, I
think sometimes things are already
written and it's meant to be and if
you're willing to have match that with
work ethic and you know, belief in it
then you got a chance.
And then uh any any favorite memories at
Central Michigan that you got?
I mean there's probably some I can't
talk about. There's probably some I
can't talk about. Um
You know, I love I love Central, right?
Uh
They gave me opportunity to come and
walk on there when they didn't have to.
You know, I earned a scholarship there.
You know, my best friends to this day
are from there. Uh
You know, I was hoping to get up there
for pro day this week. I'm not sure if I
will. It's tomorrow. Um
But
uh
I mean just being out there and like
playing with your brothers, right? Like
like I said like my best friends are
still from Central. We played together.
Like those memories of living together,
playing together,
you know, late night workouts together.
Like all those different things. Like
the little things you don't necessarily
think you're going to miss. Uh you know,
those are probably some of my some of my
best memories.
Thank you. Appreciate it.
Dave.
Hey Tyler, it's uh good to see you
again. Been a been a minute. Um just
wanted to sort of follow up on the whole
uh coming home thing I guess a little
bit. The uh did you ever have a chance
to come back to the Lions in some of the
previous times you've been in free
agency?
Um if if if so, why was this one
different that you decided? And if not,
what does it mean to finally have this
you know, towards the end of your career
this opportunity to be home?
Yeah, I have I never I've never had the
ability or the opportunity to come back
here in the past.
Uh
You know, and then when it kind of
presented like I didn't know how free
agency was going to go this year, right?
Like with the situation playing out how
it did in LA last year. Uh I was kind of
very just in interested in like how you
know, what teams were going to be
interested and and whatnot and uh you
know, watching from afar and like one
I'd obviously love to be home. Like
being home is uh still doesn't feel
real.
Uh
Two, like just what they do here with
their tight ends and in that. Uh
Three, I would like to think it's not
too close to the end of my career. I
like I think I like to think I got a
couple I got a I got I got a handful of
them left in me. Um like I was saying
earlier, right? Like I didn't get a
chance to play until year four and then
you know, last year I didn't you know,
get to play in the role that I'm used to
playing. So I really that's probably
only like 5 years on the body. So I'm
I think was that only going to like year
six right now physically. So I got I got
some time left. Uh But yeah, I got never
really had opportunity to come back to
answer the question and
uh you know, I'm just really happy that
I I that opportunity finally did come
and I'm really excited to be here. Let's
say back half of the career, not the end
of the career then.
>> There you go. I like that. I like that a
little better.
>> [laughter]
>> Um the uh you mentioned how the Lions
use their tight ends here. We all know
what what Drew Petzing did with the you
know, multiple tight end sets in
Arizona. Um
what do you just sort of envision your
role being here and and how much is you
know, was that intriguing to you to kind
of be a part of a
uh of an offense that may use um you
know, two and three tight ends a lot?
Yeah, uh you know, I just I have no idea
you know, what my role would be, right?
But I can tell you just that I'll come
in here and I plan on being the best the
best version of myself as a football
player, as a person and uh just want to
help this team however I got to help
this team, right? Like um in whatever
capacity or whatever role that is. Um
you know, all I can do is control how I
how I compete and how I you know, come
in this building every day, how I
practice every day and um
you know, whether you know,
I'm catching passes, whether I'm
blocking more, whether I'm playing
special teams, whether I'm
just mentoring or whatever whatever that
role is. Like I want to help this team
win.
Um but I definitely got a lot of good
minutes of football left in me. Last
thing, um same same sort of topic, but
just philosophically and beyond what the
Lions do with tight ends or certain
coaches. You know, we have seen more of
that 13 personnel in the NFL of late. Uh
why do you think you know, it's sort of
come full circle? Like this is the tight
end's time to shine. Why is that maybe
become a bigger part of the NFL these
days?
Yeah, I think just the way like
obviously that we've developed. You
know, I think the really unique part
about this this room. Um obviously being
new here I don't know you know, Sam and
Brock and everybody super well yet, but
uh watching them from afar and just
respecting the way they play the game.
Like as a guy that wanted to be a tight
end that be able to play every down and
be able to block and be able to run
routes. Like watching the fact that
those guys do that. Um it makes it it
makes me really excited to be here,
right? Like, nobody here just does one
thing. Like, they're they're able to do
everything and,
you know, I think that's why you see it
more, right? You can put If you can put
three tight ends out there and they can
all catch passes and they can all play
well in the run game and
and whatnot, like, it makes it very hard
to,
you know, to defend them.